I gave Feng
我给了冯科长
one last week.
最后一个星期
If Peng doesn't
就是到时候
talk by then,
他还是不开口
I'll get rid of him.
我照样把他解决掉
You're a policeman.
您是警察
How you handle cases is your expertise.
怎么办案是您的事情
As for my brother,
但是我弟弟的事情
I must resolve it myself.
只能我来解决
No one else is allowed to interfere.
谁都不许插手
Sir,
副局长
what did Mr. Hua say?
华秘书怎么说
Does he know where Hua Zhen
他知道华桢把那个女的
hid that woman?
藏哪儿了吗
What else would he say?
他还能怎么说
Of course, he denies
当然是否认得
everything cleanly.
干干净净啊
And Mr. Nakamura?
那里见先生呢
Nakamura said
里见说
it's a domestic matter of the Huas.
这是华家的家事
Now that
华梁
Hua Liang
现在是
is QX JV Corp's
七祥国货联营公司的
representative,
代表
as long as he honors the agreement,
只要生意能继续
Nakamura
里见
certainly won't displease him.
当然不会得罪了
It just leaves us
那这不是把问题
to deal with the problem?
都抛给我们了吗
Assign two men to keep an eye on Hua Zhen.
派两个人 盯着华桢
You suspect that woman
您是怀疑那个女的
is with Hua Zhen?
在华桢手里
But Mr. Nakamura said
可是里见先生说
it's their family matter.
这是华家的家事啊
Hua Liang is returning to Nanjing
华梁明天一早
tomorrow morning.
就回南京了
Whether it's his family matter or not,
是不是他的家事
we'll find out.
盯了不就知道了吗
Understood.
好的
The only chip I have
我能够坐上这张牌桌
at this poker table
唯一的筹码
is that I can
就是我能够
offer protection for their deals.
为他们的交易提供保护
Now that this woman has disappeared,
现在这个女人不见了
it would end up being my fault,
坏的全是我的事儿
and I'm the only one
最后被踢出局的
who could be kicked out in the end.
也只可能是我
Hua Liang insisted
华梁说
that his brother's matters
他弟弟的事
can only be solved by him,
只能由他来解决
and no one else can interfere.
谁也不能插手
But this is Shanghai.
但这是在上海
His words
他的话
carry no weight here.
说了不算
Got it.
明白
Mrs. Peng has been settled in
彭太太已经安顿好了
a secure house managed by the NSO.
这里是救国会的安全房
She'll stay here
在彭记者找到之前
until we locate Mr. Peng.
她就先住到这儿吧
I'll take care of her in the French Concession.
在法租界我也有个照应
Good.
好
What's wrong?
怎么了
I pointed a gun at Xiang Yuansheng.
我拿枪对着向远生了
He was the one
是他帮我
who helped me rescue Mrs. Peng.
把彭太太救出来的
Have you eaten yet?
吃饭了吗
There's a good
这儿附近有一家
French restaurant nearby.
不错的法餐厅
Let's go.
走吧
Sorry,
对不起
I forgot they close
我忘了这个时间
at this hour.
西餐厅都关门了
It's okay.
没关系啊
I'm not a big fan
反正我也不爱吃
of Western food anyway.
洋人的东西
Let's go to this noodle stall
带你吃这家面吧
I frequent.
我经常来
Boss, are you still open?
老板 还有吗
We're closed.
我打烊了呀
You go ahead.
你忙你的
I'll serve myself.
我自己来就好
Okay,
好 好
help yourself.
你自己来
You warm up by the fire. It's too cold.
你先烤会儿火 太冷了
Xiang Yuansheng has
向远生已经
already heard about
听彭太太说了
the photo from Mrs. Peng
照片的事情了
and began to suspect his brother
他已经猜到了这件事情
might be involved.
和他哥有关
So you're saying
照这么说
he can't
这件事情
distance himself from this?
跟他撇不开关系了
He might not
他未必就需要
need to.
撇开关系啊
What do you mean?
什么意思
I just found out.
我也是刚知道的
Leader Deng
邓组长以前
had proposed recruiting Xiang Yuansheng
向组织提出过
to the organization before,
要发展向远生
but we
但是之前
never initiated
考虑到风险太大
because of the high risk.
一直都没有启动计划
It might
但是我觉得
be the right time now.
现在是一个很好的时机
He is already
向远生已经是
deeply involved,
一个局中人了
and Mr. Peng's case
彭记者的事情
isn't just an organizational task.
也不完全是组织的任务
It's part of your duties as a policeman too.
也是你作为警察的任务
If he is willing
如果向远生
to get involved,
有意要参与这件事情
the organization thinks
组织认为
you two could collaborate,
你们可以合作
and we want you
也希望你从中
to observe him.
对他进行观察
The organization wants us to collaborate
组织希望我们重新合作
and me to observe him?
并且让我观察他
Why did they suddenly
组织怎么突然想起来
decide so?
让我做这件事情
I have no experience with this kind of thing.
我一点经验都没有
I requested it.
是我向组织提出申请的
Really?
真的
But I just
可是我今天
pointed a gun at him today.
刚刚拿枪对着他
If he knows
如果他知道
his brother might be involved,
这件事情跟他哥有关
he'll understand your reaction.
他会理解你的
Really?
真的吗
Let's hope so.
希望会吧
Why are you laughing?
你笑什么
Comrade Chen Hao,
陈浩同志
you really need to practice
你要好好练习一下
controlling your facial expressions.
你的表情控制了
Also,
还有
your noodles are about to burn.
你的面都快糊了
Here, have a taste.
来 尝尝
I've already had dinner.
我吃过晚饭了
I can only cook noodles,
我虽然只会做面
but I make
但我做的面
amazing taste. *said in Shanghai accent
味道灵啊
What does it mean?
什么叫“米多林”啊
It means delicious in Shanghainese.
就是好吃
It tastes amazing. *said in Shanghai accent
味道灵
Thank you.
谢谢
-Is Mrs Peng safe now? -Yes
彭太太安顿好了
I've heard about that photo.
我听说了那张照片
You must have learned it.
你应该也知道了吧
The one with my brother, a Japanese man,
我哥和一个日本人
and Tan Shiyuan
还有谭施远
all together.
在一起的照片
Yes.
对
During the time
我回电雷学校的
I was back at the S.M.C.,
那段时间
my brother came from Nanjing
我哥从南京
to visit me in Jiangyin.
来江阴找过我
He made an excuse of visiting me
表面上是给我送东西
for probing into
却突然向我问起四所
the Fourth Station and Mr. Peng's case.
和彭记者的案子
He claimed he made the inquiry on behalf of a friend
他说他是在帮一个朋友
about Mr. Peng's whereabouts.
打听彭记者的去处
But I know
但我知道
my brother doesn't
我哥不会单纯地
help anyone that way.
帮任何人打听任何事儿
He doesn't have
因为他没有
that kind of friend.
这样子的朋友
After what happened with Wei Daiqing,
魏岱擎那件事情之后
he's been particularly fearful
他特别害怕
of my having any connection to Shanghai.
我跟上海还有联系
He spares no efforts in telling me
他三番五次地叮嘱我
not to mention
不要再提
anything about Shanghai,
任何上海的事儿
yet it was he who brought it up.
结果却是他主动提起
There's only one possibility:
只有一种可能
the incident behind this
那就是背后的事情
is threatening him
已经威胁到了他
or the interests of the Hua family.
或者华家的利益
You came here today
你今天来找我
to ask what really happened
是想问彭记者失踪案
in Mr. Peng's disappearance, right?
到底发生了什么对吗
You know something, right?
你是知道些什么吧
I don't.
我不知道
I helped Mrs. Peng
我帮彭太太
on behalf of Mr. Peng's friends,
是受彭记者的朋友所托
and they are as in the dark as I am.
他们也不知道
My brother told me
我哥跟我说
Mr. Peng wasn't just missing.
彭记者不是失踪
He was secretly arrested
而是因为谋杀
for murder.
被秘密逮捕
I really can't bring myself
我实在是没有办法
to believe him.
说服自己相信他
Are you curious
你真的对这件事
about the case?
这么好奇吗
It's not about curiosity.
不是好奇
It's about unease.
是不安
I have doubts,
我心里有疑惑
and only finding Mr. Peng
只有找到了彭记者
will answer them.
才能知道答案
I'm investigating this case
我查这个案子
because I'm a police officer.
是因为我是警察
It's my job,
这是我的饭碗
something I must do.
也是我必须要做的事情
But you're different.
可你不一样
You're back at school.
你已经回到学校
You have your own duties,
你有你的任务
receiving ships, marine training,
接收舰艇 海上训练
none of which
这些事情
relate to
跟彭记者失踪案
Mr. Peng's disappearance.
没有任何关系
Do you really want to disrupt
你真的要因为一个答案
your life plans just for an answer?
打乱自己的人生规划吗
Although
虽然彭记者
Mr. Peng's disappearance
与我怎么规划
has nothing to do
自己的人生
with my personal life plans,
没有关系
If it involves my brother,
但他失踪跟我哥有关
it concerns me.
那这件事就跟我有关
I need to know the truth.
我必须知道真相
No matter
哪怕
how harsh it might be.
真相很残酷
You wouldn't be investigating alone.
要查也不是你一个人查
If you're willing,
如果你愿意
we can collaborate
我们可以合作到
until we find Mr. Peng.
找到彭记者为止
How about that?
怎么样
Do you have a lead?
你有线索
That truck
那天追彭太太的
that chased Mrs. Peng,
那辆货车
was there
我们查
for the Meng family
孟家凶杀案的时候
murder investigation.
也遇到过
Right after
当时我们
we stepped out the Japanese restaurant,
刚从日本料理店出来
a license-less truck
朝我们开黑枪的
shot at us.
也是一辆无牌货车
Last night, I followed it
昨天晚上我一直跟着它
until it disappeared
最后它开进了福华路
on Fuhua Road.
消失了
I suspect their hideout
我怀疑窝点
is on that road.
就在那条路上
Had you already planned this?
你是不是早就想好了
Promise me,
答应我
don't tell Erbai
这件事情
and the others about this.
别跟二白他们说
Since the Fourth Station was disbanded,
自从四所撤了以后
I've seldom been in touch with them.
我很少跟他们来往
Afraid of getting them into trouble?
你怕给他们惹麻烦
It's not that complicated.
没那么矫情
Tomorrow, 7 PM,
明天晚上七点
at the intersection of Fuhua Road.
福华路路口见
It's late. You should head back.
不早了 早点回去吧
Wait a minute.
等一下
Why didn't you just
在医院的时候
tell me straight at the hospital?
为什么不直接告诉我
If you had,
你如果说了
I would have handed her over to you.
我一定会把人交给你的
Which choice was harder for you?
哪个选择对你来说更难
What?
什么
Have a gun pointed at you,
是用枪指着没得选
or to choose between helping your brother
还是在帮哥哥
and helping me,
跟帮我之间
which is harder?
做一个选择更难
Welcome back.
欢迎回来
Mr. Hua,
华秘书
your ticket back to Nanjing for tomorrow
明天回南京的票
has been booked.
已经订好了
As usual,
按您的习惯
first flight in the morning.
订的是明早第一班
Change it to the afternoon flight.
改成明天下午的吧
I have a friend to meet.
我要去见一个朋友
Understood.
是
Hua Zhen,
华桢
who was the girl waiting for you that night?
那天等你的女孩儿
Who is she to you?
是你什么人
What girl?
什么女孩儿
I don't know her.
我又不认识
Dressed something like
穿得像警服
a police uniform but not quite,
又不是警服
standing alone
大晚上一个人
under the tree on that chilly night.
在那树下等着
Her face all red from the cold.
脸都冻红了
When did this happen?
什么时候的事儿
The same night your brother
就是你哥哥来找你的
came to see you.
那天晚上
She was asking us
她问我们
if you got home safely.
你安全回去了没有
I thought
我还以为
you knew about it.
你知道这事儿呢
Yuansheng!
远生
Erbai?
二白
He's a friend. You guys go ahead.
我朋友 你们先去
Okay. Let's go.
行 走吧
What are you doing here?
你怎么在这儿
Yuansheng,
远生
Dongbao got hurt at the dock.
冬宝在码头受伤了
Well,
那个
folks from the Fourth Station want to visit him.
四所的人想去看看他
Are you coming?
你去吗
Okay.
好
Wait a sec.
等我一下
I'll request a car.
我去申请辆车
No need.
不用
I have a car, remember?
咱有车 你忘了
I'm a taxi driver now.
现在咱是出租车司机
Get in. Let's go.
上车 快快
How did Dongbao get hurt?
冬宝怎么受伤了
He was working in the warehouse at the docks.
冬宝在码头仓库干活
Probably starving
可能饭吃得太少了
and too much weight,
东西又扛得太多
ended up fainting
晕过去了
and injuring his hand.
把手就给摔伤了
Has he thought about changing jobs?
他有想过换个工作吗
Change jobs?
换工作
That kid,
那孩子呀
he really fell in love with being a cop,
当警察当出感情了
submitted a retention application,
交了留用申请
and has been waiting for a new assignment ever since.
一直在等着总局的分配
But up to now,
可是到现在了
there hasn't been any news.
一点儿消息都没有
Now,
他现在呀
he's just waiting
就是一边等消息
and making a living.
一边挣钱
So is Yu,
小玉也是
working hard at the docks
整天起早贪黑地
from dawn till dusk.
跟着他码头干活
He just wants to open
他就想给小玉
a breakfast shop for Yu.
开个早餐铺子
So he could get back
到时候他再能
to being a police officer,
回去当警察
giving birth to a couple of kids,
将来再生个一儿半女
what happy days.
那小日子 多幸福
Honestly,
其实吧
we bring stuff to Dongbao
我们给冬宝送东西啊
not because he can't afford it.
也不是因为他买不起
We just hope
就是希望小两口
they save up their money
把钱都攒起来
to have
能够早点儿过上
a better life sooner.
那种好点儿的日子
They will make it.
肯定会的
They're working so hard
他们这么努力
won't go unrewarded.
总不可能没有回报吧
Exactly.
对
Erbai.
二白哥
Minmin.
珉敏
Where is chief and the others	?
所长他们人呢
They haven't arrived yet.
还没来呢
Alright,
行吧
then let's wait for them.
那咱等会儿他们
We'll go in together.
一块儿进去
These guys,
你说这几个人
they all agreed to come see Dongbao,
说好的来看冬宝
but they're not showing any urgency.
一点儿也不积极
Agreed on the timing
这都说好的时间
but have no sense of punctuality.
一点儿时间观念没有
This is unbelie...
你说这
I'll go...
我去冬
I'll just...
我 我去
I'll see if they're coming.
我去路口看看他们
That day, it was my brother
那天是我哥
who drove me back to the dorm.
送我回的宿舍
That day at the hospital,
医院那天
it was him who took me back.
是我哥送我回的宿舍
He just wanted me
他只是要我
not to get involved with Mr. Peng's case
不要管彭记者的案子
and didn't make things difficult for me.
没有为难我
I'm okay.
我没事儿
That day,
那天
the Captain told me you were fine.
队长跟我说了你没事儿
so I went straight home.
我就直接回家了
Why are you laughing?
你笑什么
We are waiting for you.
就等你们两个
Come on.
快快快
You two have
你说你们两个
lost track of time.
一点儿时间观念也没有
Apologize
来晚了
Just as usual.
老规矩啊
My share.
来
Here's mine.
我的
Let's go.
走走走
That's a lot of money.
这么多钱
Dongbao,
冬宝
what did the doctor say?
大夫怎么说
He said nothing serious.
大夫说没啥事儿
I just need to have some days off.
就是休养两天就行了
Watch this.
你看
Listen to me,
我就跟你说
you should take it more seriously
别不当个事儿啊
and rest for at least three months.
伤筋动骨一百天
Just have a good rest
你就好好歇着啊
and we will
有什么活
help you with your chores.
我们都帮你干了 好吧
Yes.
对
Thank you Director.
谢谢所长 谢谢
Director, Erbai,
所长
have some water.
二白哥你们先喝水
I'll bring more.
我再去倒啊
Don't bother.
不用了别忙活了
It's okay.
没事儿
I'm supposed to...
你看这 我这就是应该
Yu,
来 小玉
we hope this can help you.
这大家的一点儿心意
Minmin you don't need to...
珉敏姐你这是做什么
Take it.
你收好
No I can't.
这我不能收
Dongbao told
冬宝说过
we can't rely on you anymore.
不能再要你们接济了
Do you consider me a sister?
我是不是你姐
If you do, you should accept it.
是你姐就得听我的
Here.
来
Take it.
拿着
But I...
这 我这
Dongbao,
冬宝
Minmin gives us money again.
这珉敏姐又给我们塞钱
Minmin,
珉敏
we can't accept it.
珉敏 使不得
Please take it back.
收起来
Every time you come
你们每次来
to visit us you bring so many
都给我们带那么多东西
food and money.
还给我们塞钱
No more, I refuse.
这次不行 说啥不行
Put it back.
你收好
What about the food you served us?
那我们隔三差五来吃饭
It must cost a lot.
那不花钱
Yeah, here's
对呀 我们
the payment of the meals.
饭钱这是
But
不是
the ingredients
你们每次来
are given by you guys.
米面油粮都送了
You don't need to pay.
你 收啥钱嘛
Erbai told us
听二白说
you and Yu
你和小玉
want to start up a breakfast shop
想开个早餐铺子
and we want to invest in it.
就当是我们的投资了
Yes.
对对对
Here's our investment.
这是我们入股的钱
So just accept it.
听话 拿好
If you insist on not accepting,
你这要是再不收
we will leave.
我们就走了啊
I'm leaving now.
现在就走
Don't go.
走什么 走走走
Listen to me.
都听我的
Yu, take the money.
小玉 把这钱收着
Dongbao,
冬宝
take it.
收着
Take it.
拿着拿着
OK, thank all of you guys.
行 那这钱我就拿着了
But we should make a deal
但是咱得说好了啊
that every time you come in the future,
你们以后每次来
I will use this money to buy meat
我就拿这钱给大家买肉
and cook soy-braised pork for you.
做红烧肉吃
Deal?
这总行了吧
When it comes to the pork,
一说红烧肉
I feel hungry now.
我这真有点儿饿了
I'll cook.
那我去做饭
Go ahead.
快去快去 做饭去
Director,
所长
take a seat.
里边坐
Be careful.
你别瞎忙叨了
Take good care of yourself.
你好好休息吧
I'm fine.
没事儿
Yuansheng, be my guest.
向警官 您自己坐啊
I'm home.
我到家了
Can we talk?
有时间谈谈吗
I don't want to.
我不想谈
Go home.
回去吧
Why didn't you write to me?
你为什么不给我写信
Didn't you receive my letters?
你没收到我的信
I had been waiting for your letter
我等你的信
for one week,
等了一个星期
two weeks,
两个星期
then more than a month.
等了一个多月
Now here you are
你现在突然回来
but what for?
有什么用
We are
我们都已经
not where we were.
各自往前走了
I wrote to you since the first day
我从回学校的第一天
I went back to school.
就给你写信
One letter every three days
三天一封
and more than ten letters in total.
我一共写了十几封
Did you write?
你给我写信了
I did,
我写了
and I was also waiting for your reply.
我也在等你的回信
I thought you were engaged
我以为你回南京
in Nanjing
订婚了
and
所以
shouldn't have written letters to me.
才不该给我回信
My brother told you I was engaged?
我哥跟你说我订婚了
Are you?
所以你订婚了
Do you hope so?
你希望吗
I don't know.
我不知道
Think it over
那你就用你的木鱼脑袋
with your blockhead.
好好想想
You can always talk
你遇到任何事儿
to me,
你都可以直接告诉我
and ask about anything
你想知道什么
you want to know directly.
你就直接问我
Why assuming
你为什么要在那个地方
with your head in the clouds.
自以为
I wonder what else
你这脑袋里
are there in your head.
到底还藏了多少东西
I wish you were engaged.
我希望你订婚
You'd better think twice before answering.
你最好想清楚了再回答
I couldn't
我想得
be clearer.
清楚得不能再清楚了
Before I adore you,
我在喜欢你之前
I got the last place
哪怕做什么事情
for whatever I did.
都是最后一名
I took police examination
考警察考了三年
for three years and failed.
也没有考上
At least I was happy at that time.
但是我每天都很开心
But now,
可是我现在
I wish I were muddleheaded.
我想稀里糊涂的
I cannot.
都不行了
Before you adore me?
喜欢我之前
Yes.
对
Now you know
所以你知道我为什么
why I don't want to see you anymore?
再也不想见到你了吧
If there was a day I don't want to see you,
如果有一天我不想见你
the only reason would be
只可能是因为
I don't like you anymore.
我不喜欢你了
Hope that help
而不是像你现在这样
remove the blind
脑袋里想一些
and disorderly conjectures in your head.
乱七八糟的东西
You...
你
You said I make blind
你说我想
and disorderly conjectures,
乱七八糟的东西
and I have a block head.
你说我木鱼脑袋
What about you?
那你就不木鱼脑袋吗
If letters couldn't reach me,
你不能给我写信
why didn't you
那你想联系我
try other methods to reach me?
就找不到别的方式了吗
You bastard!
你个小兔崽子
Who do you think you are?
你以为你是什么东西
Dad!
爸爸
Get away!
你让开
No.
不行
Run!
你快跑
Don't escape!
你不要跑啊你啊
Dad!
爸爸
How dare you?
你敢走
Who do you think you are?
你以为你是谁啊
Dad!
爸爸
Jerk!
混蛋
Don't be mad.
消消气
The broom is gone.
你说这扫把都没了
We only have one broom.
就一个扫把
I think you forget
是不是不知道
who is your elder sister.
谁是姐姐 谁是妹妹啦
Tell me
告诉我
what did you do
你们两个今天晚上
in the middle of night.
干吗去了
None of your business.
你管得着吗
Give it to me.
给我
Luo Qinqin.
骆勤芹
Garbage collection!
收垃圾
Who's that?
谁
Hold.
等着
I've told you
我不是说了吗
I'll pay you
房租我下个月
the rent next month.
肯定会给你
Hello, are you Mr. Wei?
您好 是魏先生吧
Who are you?
你谁啊
I don't think I know you.
我不认识你吧
I am Jin.
我姓金
I was introduced to meet you.
有人介绍我来拜访您
I know
我知道
you've left
您从
the investigation team of Shanghai
淞沪警备司令部侦查队
Garrison Command.
离开了
But your great ability
但是您在抓捕共产党
to capture communists
方面的能力
shouldn't go ignored.
不应该就此埋没
I'm here today
我这次来就是想
to ask you
问一问魏先生
do you still have interest
是否还感兴趣
in working as an intelligence agent.
继续做情报方面的工作
You know I've left
你知道我离开了
then you must know
那我为什么离开
why I left.
你也知道了吧
I offended
我
the Undersecretary of Ministry of Military Affairs,
得罪了军政部次长
as well as
我还得罪了
the secretary of Office of Aides.
侍从室的秘书
My political future
我的政治前途
has been ruined.
完蛋了
I don't think so.
这倒未必
This time I'll invite you
这次想请魏先生
to a place
去的地方
where the Chairman Chiang serves as the president
由蒋委员长任社长
and under his direct leadership.
直接领导
What are you talking about?
你在跟我说什么
The Shanghai Station under the Secret Service Office
复兴社特务处
of the Revival Society.
上海站
I know you haven't given up
我知道您一直
on investigating Hua Zhen.
没有放弃调查华桢
My people told me
我的人告诉我
you are
他们最近总看到
frequent near a
您在一间
public phone booth lately.
公用电话亭附近
The public phone booth...
公用电话亭
That public phone booth
那个公用电话亭
is the only omission
是我调查华桢的时候的
when I investigated him.
唯一疏漏
The communist named Zhang Runjin
那个共产党张润金
was in the hospital.
当时他在医院里
He called the public phone booth
他在九点零六分的时候
at 9:06 in the morning.
给这个公用电话亭
Look at this.
打过电话
I was putting all my energy
我当时把所有精力
into investigating Xiang Yuansheng
都放在了向远生
and the belt,
和皮带上
having neglected the phone booth.
没有细查
When I went over it
后来我细细想了想
I realized
才反应过来
why Zhang Runjin
那姓张的
insisted to call a public phone booth
被人捅成那个样子了
even though he was
浑身流血
stabbed with a knife
还要给个公用电话亭
and bleeding all over.
打电话
Why!
为什么
Because this is their
因为这是他们的
hidden contact means.
隐蔽联络方式
In other words,
换而言之
his associate
他的同党
was near
就在那个
the public phone booth.
公用电话亭附近
And now you have the chance
那您现在就有机会
to repair the omission.
弥补这个疏漏
Hua Zhen is in Shanghai.
华桢来上海了
If you prefer
如果您愿意
to join in the Secret Service Office,
加入复兴社特务处
I will put you
我给您的任务
on investigating Hua Zhen
就是继续调查华桢
and digging out
并且查清
all the communists related to him.
所有跟他相关的共产党
He is in Shanghai now.
他现在就在上海
Yes.
在
You are...
你是
Are you dispatched by Secretary Guo
你是 郭秘书长派过来
to reach me?
派来找我的
Secretary Guo is not the only one
想跟您合作的
who needs you.
可不止郭秘书长一位
My boss is Mr. Yu,
我的老板姓愚
"Yu" for slow-witted wisdom in English.
大智若愚的愚
Whereas you are
既然魏先生
meant to
本来也打算
continue investigating Hua Zhen,
继续调查华桢
why don't we
那不如
work together.
我们合作
Here's the outlay,
这是一点经费
a sign of sincerity from Mr. Yu.
也是愚先生的诚意
Come and report for duty
如果您愿意的话
if you want to tomorrow.
明天就可以去报到
I was deserted
我从淞沪警备司令部
from Shanghai Garrison Command
离开的时候
and you must know it.
情况你也知道
Like a stray dog.
就像一条丧家之犬一样
So I'm curious
魏某人就好奇了
What's in me
你们
that attracts
愚先生
Mr. Yu?
看中我什么了
Have you heard of National Salvation Organization?
魏先生听过救国会吧
Not an expert,
了如指掌谈不上
But I have been
但是魏某人
investigating CPC
调查共产党
for more than seven years.
也有七八年了
The NSO was one of my targets.
其中也调查过救国会
Back in those days,
这段时间
I did collect much information
关于救国会的情报
about the NSO.
我也积攒了不少
We heard some news
我们听到了一些消息
Hua Zhen is in close contact
华桢这次来上海
with Pro-Communist individuals
和救国会里的亲共人士
in the NSO
往来密切
There might be some communists.
其中可能就有共产党
If we start form the NSO,
如果从救国会开始查起
Mr. Wei,
魏先生
you are our best choice.
就是最合适的人选
But this time
只不过这一次
we hope
我们希望
to change the sequence.
能够换一下步骤
We should first figure out
先查清楚
the communists around Hua Zhen.
华桢身边的共产党
When I was in the Garrison Command
在警备司令部的时候
I'd proved the two people,
我已经证明了
Deng Mingyuan and Zhang Runjin
跟华桢来往甚密的
who were close to Hua Zhen
邓铭远 张润金
are both communists.
全是共产党
How could Hua Zhen be innocent?
他怎么可能清白
If it were not for his powerful family
要不是他后面有个华家
I was supposed to pull him down.
当时他就被我扳倒了
Why do you
到现在了
still take a wrong path
你们怎么还拐弯抹角
and investigate communists around him?
去查他身边的共产党
Why not
为什么不能
inquire into him directly?
干脆直接查华桢
Hua Zhen must be suspicious
华桢肯定是有问题的
so he is
他一定是
our final objective.
我们的最终目标
But Mr. Yu suggests
但是愚先生的建议
we check from people around him.
从他身边的人开始查起
That will be easier.
会更容易一些
What if
如果
What if I can
如果我有能力
get you the evidence
我拿出证据
to prove Hua Zhen is a communist,
我证明华桢就是共产党
Does your
你们
Mr. Yu
愚先生
have the ability
有没有能力
to prevent the Huas from interfering?
保证华家不插手
Mr. Yu reaches you
愚先生就是有这个能力
because he has the confidence.
才让我来请您呢
There's only one requirement
愚先生只有一个条件
that you need to keep everything in secret.
这次侦查必须秘密进行
You can use forces
您可以调用
of the Secret Service.
特务处的人力
But all the intelligence
但是所有跟华桢
about Hua Zhen
有关的一切情报
must be reported to me first
只能通过我
and I'll transfer it to Mr. Yu.
向他单独汇报
No leaks.
不得外泄
Otherwise,
否则
we'll terminate the commission.
合作终止
Where should I go tomorrow?
明天去哪里报到
The Anqi Beer Company in French Concession.
法租界 安琪啤酒公司
I'll be waiting for you.
我在那儿等您